# RODRIGO SOUSA MARQUES

# Data Science | Business Intelligence

Data Scientist in Cannabis Market Research field. I can say that I'm curious by nature and always thrilled to challenge "unsolvable problems", an out-ofthe-box thinker who loves to create and explore new ideas and perspectives. Someone who knows when and how to adapt to keep evolving. I've found in Data Science the perfect environment to do what I love be; be challenged and learn everyday. -> Skilled in Data Science. Business Intelligence, Data Analytics, Power BI, SQL, Python, DAX, Machine Learning, ETL, GIT, among others. Fluent in English and Portuguese and basic French and Spanish.

rmarques.tech@gmail.com

+55 63 99230.2552

Palmas - TO, Brazil



hthttps://rmarqueso.github.io/

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Data Consultant**

wDiscover

11/2020 - Present

Pinhais - PR, Brazil

#### **Data Scientist**

Pistil Data

08/2021 - Present

San Francisco - CA, USA

Founded by executives from Google, Twitter, and Intel, Pistil Data is developing SaaS services for one of the fastest-growing industries in the world: cannabis. We are unique in our application of cutting-edge technology to an industry that has increasing needs for data and insight.

Value to the Company

- Responsible to produce high-quality code for the existing projects and new ones to support the customer and business team to improve the platform.
- Collaborate closely with the technical team to integrate and productionize data science deliverable (e.g. models, data output, data quality).
- Python (Pandas, Scikit Learn, Scipy, Seaborn, SQLAlchemy, df2gspread, Plotly, Matplotlib, etc), SQL, Git, Azure data studio, GSuite, Hubspot.

# **Data Science & Business Intelligence Analyst**

TKSolution | Tok&Stok

08/2020 - 08/2021

São Paulo - SP, Brazil

Value to the Company

- I tackled Data Science and Business Intelligence challenges driving intelligence, strategy, innovation, and valuable solutions by combining ETL, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, and Machine Learning.
- Developed of intelligent cubes (SSAS); Managerial Reports (Power BI and Reporting Services - Back and Front-end); Data governance management and dealt with data extraction and manipularion on Oracle/Snowflake/Web/APIs.
- SQL, PL/SQL, Pvthon, DAX, M.Power Bi, DBT, SSMS, SSAS, SSRS, Git, Oracle, Snowflake, Gsuite, Jira, Confluence, AWS (Glue, S3, Database Migration Service, Cloudwatch).

# **Electrical Engineering Intern - Power & Load Forecasting** Energisa

12/2018 - 12/2019

Palmas - TO. Brazil

Value to the Company

- Improved insights generation and decision making with visualizations for the historical behavior of Tocantins power grid, in Power BI;
- Main responsible for the analysis of load and power flow data for the entire State of Tocantins - I carried out dozens of studies to forecast the annual behavior of Tocantins electrical system up to the year 2035;

#### **EDUCATION**

## MBA in Business Intelligence

**UNIMAIS** - Faculdade Educamais

01/2020 - 01/2021

Brazil

#### **Electrical Engineering BS**

UniCatólica - Centro Universitário Católica do Tocantins

07/2016 - 12/2019 Palmas - TO. Brazil

# **SKILLS**

Python, PL / SQL, DAX, M, Git, Unix dash

Data Science, Analytics, Power BI, DataViz

Leadership, Teamwork, Lean Six Sigma, Agile

Critical, Creative and Adaptive Thinking

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### Awarded with exchange program in USA (09/2014 - 12/2015)

Sponsored by CAPES/CNPq as a top student of Universidade Federal do Tocantins. Sandwich undergraduation in Electrical Engineering at Eastern Washington University, WA.

#### Summer Internship in Lean Enterprise Systems - University of Tennessee (06/2015 - 07/2015)

Project implemented at Comercial Vehicle Group (CVG): -Reduced waiting time by 10.79% in CVG's testing lab; Solved the problems of management processes, mitigating rework;

#### Publication on Brazilian Journal of Development 2

Intelligent Access and Electronics Control using Microcontroller ATMEGA238P Seeking for Energy Efficiency -Brazilian Journal of Development, v.6,n. 8, p. 63859-63867 -Qualis B2 Magazine

## CERTIFICATES

Unified Data Essentials

Databricks

Deploying Scalable ML for Data Science

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Udemv

**Business Analysis Foundations** 

International Institute of Business Analysis - IIBA

C2 Proficient English - Standard English Test EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Bilinaual Proficiency

Portuguese

Native Proficiency

French

**Elementary Proficiency** 

Spanish

Elementary Proficiency